# **Alejandro Cortorreal**

Full-stack Developer

Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic (UTC-4) (+1) 8492841274

<u>alejandrocortorreal18@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/alejandro-cortorreal/</u> <u>https://github.com/alexwebjr</u>

Full-Stack Web Developer with more than 4 years of professional experience, mainly using **C#, .NET, JavaScript, Node.js and SQL.** I have experience working in different sectors such as startups, EdTech, and Government.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **9-1-1, Full-stack Developer** — October 2021 - Current

- Improved employee management time through the development of a resource planning system for the HR department.
- Improved the survey creation time through the development of a dynamic survey application that allows the administrator to manage dynamic forms so that they can later be filled out by quality agents.
- Reduced by 95% the number of bugs from different applications of the institution through maintenance and ticket solution.

Tech Stack: JavaScript, C#, Asp.Net, DevExpress, PHP, SCRUM, MSSQL, Semantic UI, Bootstrap

#### **UNIBE, Supervisor E-learning Platforms** — August 2020 - October 2021

- Supervised the process of enabling the virtual space to teach online classes. Making it possible for the university to teach all its subjects virtually in times of covid.
- Led a team of 3 supporters and 1 analyst.
- Improved the teaching portal through the redesign of the web page.

Tech Stack: JavaScript, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Materialize CSS, WordPress

#### **WELLTECH, Full-stack Developer** — May 2019 - August 2020

- Developed the web application for an appraisal company. Developing quality code, integrating Zoho CRM API, and AZUL
- Translated to C# a geolocation library written in PHP.
- Designed the web portal for different clients.

Tech Stack: JavaScript, C#, Asp.Net, PHP, Bootstrap, Zoho CRM, API RESTful, jQuery

#### **SOCIAL BOIL, Front-end Developer** — July 2019 - December 2019

- Improved and optimized the loading time and the positioning in browsers by updating and optimizing the web pages of different clients.
- Designed the web portal for different sports federations and other organizations.

Tech Stack: JavaScript, C#, PHP, WordPress, Umbraco, HTML, CSS

## FREELANCER, Full-stack Developer — January 2016 - Current

- Improved service administration time for an auto detailing company by designing an online booking website.
- Improved the response time to services for a car rental company by designing a website where customers can rent vehicles online.
- Designed and developed a landing page integrating WooCommerce with Zoho CRM.
- Improved the brand image of an influencer through the design of her website.
- Designed and developed the website for a lens distributor company.

Tech Stack: JavaScript, C#, PHP, WordPress, HTML, CSS

## **PROJECTS**

Job Portal – https://github.com/Alexwebjr/Empleos - 2022

• Designed and developed an app to publish job offers, with dynamic management of ads with google ads. **Tech Stack:** Node.js, React, Redux, Material-UI, Sequelize

Event Portal – https://github.com/Alexwebjr/Natours - 2022

• Developed a web app to handle events, including payments with the stripe API. **Tech Stack:** Node.js, Express, MongoDB

## **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Advanced: C#, JavaScript; Intermediate: PHP

Frameworks Tools: Advanced: .NET; Intermediate: Vue.js, Laravel.

Data Base: Intermediate: MongoDB, MySQL, MSSQL; Basic: AWS, Firebase.

**Tools:** <u>Advanced:</u> Git, WordPress, Express, Bootstrap, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Semantic UI; <u>Intermediate:</u> Vuex, DevExpress, Umbraco, Material-UI, Tailwind CSS, Mongoose, Socket.io; <u>Basic:</u> GraphQL, Redux, Pinia, AWS, Microservices, Unit Test, Jest, Vitest.

Agile: SCRUM, Trello

**Languages**: Intermediate: English; Native: Spanish.

# **EDUCATION**

**O & M DOMINICAN UNIVERSITY** – Santo Domingo. *Bachelor of Science in Computer Systems Engineering, July 2016*